[Music]
icICI Potential Signature
Plan How much does this insurance plan help us in
long-term wealth creation and
how much does it
help us in achieving our financial goals? Let's review this policy.
Hi, I am Ramalingam
Holistic Investment. The aim of our website is to help
investors make the right investment
decisions quickly. Before reviewing this
ICICI Potential Signature Plan,
before making such a decision whether to buy it or not, let's talk about the
key features of this policy. Let's see
what kind of policy this policy is.
So, this is a
kind of ULIP plan. Let's
tell you
why. The amount collected in this fund is
a portion of your life.
Another portion goes towards
your market linked
investment, the stock
market as well as the money market
based investment, so let's
say it's a unit linked insurance plan. So this is
a policy that is subject to the fluctuations in the market. There
are three variants of this policy. You
can pay a single premium and wait for it to
get the benefit at maturity. Or you can pay a limited
premium for 5 years, 7 years, etc.
Apart from that, you can
wait for 5 years, 10 years, 20 years, etc. and
get the benefit at maturity. Or if the policy term is 20 years, you can
pay the premium for the entire 20 years. When the 20 years are over, you will
get the maturity benefit. In this type of
multiple options, you have  There
are variants, another
variant is the whole life policy, throw
out your life time, a
policy that gives you life cover, so there are
multiple options, this policy is
available, this policy
has an option like SWB, you
need funds regularly beyond a point of time,
then how much money you need,
you can take it monthly,
quarterly or annually,
you can take it from here, partial withdrawal is also an
option that can be taken after five years, this
policy has an option, I have already
told you that this is a unit
link insurance plan, let's
say that this is a unit link insurance plan, when you do it, you
can invest in the underlying stock market, money market, stock market paste, there are
funds, money market
paste, there are funds  What is the performance
of those funds since inception?
What returns have they given in the last five years? That is the data
you are
looking at now. If
you have taken the options that can be stock market funds, then there are Focus 50 Funds,
Opportunities Funds, Value
Enhancer Funds, Multi-Cap Growth
Funds, Blue Chip Funds, etc.
So what are the CAGR returns of these funds? There are
some funds that are money market funds without stock market. If you have looked at those
funds, income funds, money
market funds, secure
opportunities funds are in that
category. If
you have seen their performance in the last five years, then it is
between 5% to 7%. Balanced
funds are a mixed
combination of fixed income plus
equity.  If you look at the funds that can be invested in both, and the
returns,
some funds have come up to 06%,
while some funds have come up to 9% or 10%.
So, there
are many underlying funds that can give mixed performance. Here, we
can pick and choose which
fund to invest in and
how much allocation to give to it.
You
can decide what kind of
benefits the investor will get in this policy. If you
look at the two types of
benefits, one is that if the
investor
dies, then
what amount will the nominee get as death benefit.
Second, what benefit will be available at maturity? So, first, let's
see what our death benefit is. Death benefit is
a three-way valuation insurance.  The company
will put in the highest
value of the three and
settle that value as a death benefit to the nominee. So now when
you
come and see the death benefit, first come the sum
assured, what is the sum assured in this policy? There is
a first valuation, and the second comes the
underlying
funds of this fund, we invest in our different equity
funds, what is the
valuation of that fund,
what is its value as of today? The second
value is the
third, which is 105% of the total premiums
paid. Whatever premium we have paid so far,
that is 105%, so put in these three
values ​​and settle the highest value of these three values ​​as a death benefit
to the nominee. So now we  We have seen what the highest value of the death benefit is in the
three valuations. Let
us look at an example of what the maturity benefit is.
For example, if someone pays 15% for 15 years and
pays 2 lakhs of premium,
what will be the maturity value of the fund? Even if the
CAGR is 8%, 8% is the highest return that can be obtained when generating the benefit illustration on the icci
potential website. Let us assume that the
best case scenario return is 8%, and that 8%
return is our assumption. Then the
return that we can get is 2822
lakhs, and that maturity value is
obtained. Okay, so now we
have seen what the maturity benefit is. Now this  Is the maturity
benefit sufficient? Is it
sufficient to beat inflation? Will
this maturity benefit provide
good returns overall? Is it a better
risk-adjusted return? So,
we need to know that, so
we can only get it if we compare this investment with some other investments.
Before that, let's see what IRR this return has worked out for us. Let's see the
internal rate of return. If you have seen it, even though the
underlying fund has given us an 8% CAGR, the
net return that works out for us is
554%.
How can an investor
get only 554% when the CAGR is 8%? That's
the question that must be on your mind. The
answer to that is what you
are looking at in this slide. The reason for this is that this
fund has a lot of charges.  They charge
fund allocation charges, fund
management charges, fund
administration charges, mortality charges,
discontinuance charges. When you
enter this fund, there are
charges,
premium allocation charges, policy
administration charges,
fund
management charges for managing the fund, throw it out, you come
out of the fund, you discriminate,
then the charges are for
providing life cover, life cover charges, here the
charges for providing life cover, fund management
charges are acceptable, we
can come and take it, it is
reasonable, we can come and take it, but
premium allocation charge, policy
administration charges  You have come and seen all that, the
discontinuance charges, they are
very extravagant, they are
very high amounts, do
you think an investor needs this? No, this is a premium, it is there to
benefit the insurance agents and the bancassurance or the bank, that is, to benefit the
distributors,
but there are no
charges that can provide long-term benefits to an investor. That is
why there are so many charges.
Even if this policy gives 8% cross GC GR, when it works
out for the investor, it
works out only 554%. Okay,
now it is 554%. It has a return that can be equal to a bank FD.
This is a return that can beat inflation.
If we see that, then
definitely come and invest in our stock
market.  Is this the
best return that can be invested for a long term of 15 years? Is
this the risk adjusted return? Okay, so
what can we do with this? If so, let's
compare this investment option with another investment that can give similar stock market returns.
Before that, let's
come and find out some of the benefits that can be found in it. One is that we
have tax benefits, there is section 80c
benefit, and on maturity
we also get benefits.
You can make those kinds of changes between equity and debt to equity. You
can come and make those switching
options. If you come and
see the negatives, there are no guaranteed
returns in this policy. Is even a 557% return a
guaranteed return for you?  There
are many charges that come and go, as we have already
seen, it makes your returns
worse. There
is a minimum locking period of 5 years, and until then there are
discount charges.
Everyone sells the policy by saying that the maturity proceeds are tax-free in general insurance.
But if your annual premium is
more than 25 lakhs, the maturity proceeds will be treated as
capital gain for you. Is this
an important matter that we need
to look into?
Everyone
buys insurance policies by saying that the maturity benefits are tax-free. But it is valid as long as your annual premium is less than
25 lakhs. If it is more than
25 lakhs,
it is not applicable according to the new tax rules. Okay, so as
I said before, this
policy is one of ours.  You can also compare with ILS Mutual
Fund
because ILS Mutual Fund also
gives ATC benefit when we invest and that too is a stock
market based investment.
So in this policy, I have taken 15 lakhs from the
first year premium to give you life cover. After making a profit,
you will get only the balance amount. You invest in
ILS Mutual Fund. In the first year, you
invest only ₹50,000. The balance
15 lakhs goes to give you life cover.
Because ICICI
Potential Signature Plan gives life cover to an
investor and also
gives maturity benefit. So we
bought a separate term insurance policy to give life cover.  We
invest in our ELSS, if
you look at the maturity benefit, it is 47
lakhs. It is 47 lakhs.
Even if you pay all the capital gains taxes, you
can get 4432
lakhs. So you are
taking the same amount of risk, but here you get
almost double the benefit. There
are possibilities of 80 to 90% increase in return for you in ELSS. If you look at the
return that we have assumed for ELSS, we have
assumed our 12% CAGR based on our fast track record. This has come to us
based on our fast track record and in some cases, even more than
15% has been given by ELS mutual
funds.  We
assumed 12% on the conservative side, but
we
know that this is subject to market ups and downs. So when we compare ELSS
Mutual Funds,
term insurance plus
ELSS Mutual Funds is giving much better benefits to investors. So now as an
investor,
what is our final verdict on this policy?
If so, one, does it give
us an inflation-adjusted return? If so, then no. If so, does it give us a
risk-adjusted return? If so,
why are there so
many high charges in this policy?
Second, there is
no flexibility in this policy. Every year, we do not have to
commit a premium.
We have to pay the same premium in this policy. We
cannot easily get out of this policy.  But
I am investing in an ELSS mutual fund today. If
I am not confident in its performance next year, I
have options to invest in HDFC or Axis Bank. I have the flexibility to
invest more or less every year.
This is not in this insurance
policy. So if you are a risk-tolerant investor,
you are a risk-
taking investor, an aggressive
investor, then you can invest in an ELSS
mutual fund plus term
insurance policy. I am
a
conservative investor. I am a risk-averse investor. I do not want to take risk.
I want to take less risk. If you want to take PPF plus term insurance, then
you can invest in a PPF plus
term insurance policy.  You can invest in the policy
or you can include a combination of three products like term
insurance plus PPF plus ILS
mutual fund and
you can also invest in an astrology fund. So finally, can
you invest in this policy or not? You have come to
this question and you have
seen my answer. If so, then definitely this
policy should be
avoided. Why then, you will get poor
returns, high
charges, returns that do not even help you beat inflation.
So,
you can definitely avoid this policy.
This policy also has a
very detailed analysis and
research report on it. It is available on our website, in the black post, and I
have given a description for it below this video. If you
click on it, you will get more information.
You can definitely come and see the detailed analysis. If
you have any questions about this policy
or any other investment
option,
then you can
also book a free appointment with our financial planner. In
this
appointment,
you
can clarify your requirements, your goals, and any doubts you may have about your existing investments. This is a
complete free financial
planning appointment. The
registration link for that free booking is in the description box below this video. You can
book an appointment for a 30-minute discussion right now and you can
also talk about finances.
We have been organizing regular investment
webinars.
Complimentary
webinars are coming soon.  We have come up with a
short schedule and
have given a link for it in the description of this video.
You can reserve your ticket by providing your name and email ID. If you
liked this video and thought it was useful,
then just give it
a thumbs up. If you think
this video will be useful to someone in your social circle,
please
share it. So that you don't miss such useful
videos, please
subscribe to our channel. Thank you.
See you in the next video.